☆Bean.炜健☆ 作品
-=圣城家园 CnSCG 荣誉出品=-
hd.cnscg.com
滚蛋 你这个狗娘养的 杂种
Go fuck yourself, you son of a bitch. Bastard!
耶和华是我的牧者 我必不至缺乏
The Lord is my shepherd. I shall not want.
愿你的名受显扬 愿你的国来临
Hallowed be thy name. Thy kingdom come.
原你的旨意奉行 你妈的
Thy will be done, you fuck!
求你今天赏给我们日用的食粮
Give us this day our daily bread,
如同我们宽恕别人一样
as we forgive those who trespass against us.
耶稣 拿撒勒人耶稣
Jesus, Jesus the Nazarene.
耶稣 拿撒勒人 去死吧 去死吧 去死吧
Jesus, the nazarene. Go to hell. Go to hell. Go to hell.
去死 去死 去死 去死
Hell! Hell! Hell! Hell! Hell! Hell!
吉姆 你不是打算
Jim, you're not going to waste
一天都躺床上吧
the whole day lying around, are you?
妈 我起了 那破钟坏了
Ma, I'm up. The loony alarm went off.
拉上窗帘
Well, close the blinds.
别看她也别听她的
Don't look at her and don't listen to her.
怎么可能听不见啊
How could I not?
拿撒勒人耶稣
Jesus the Nazarene.
保佑妓女 保佑理发师
Mary the whore. Mary the hairdresser.
保佑理发师 天父 在...
Mary the hairdresser. Our Father, Who art...
嘿 女人
Hey, lady!
闭嘴
Shut up!
篮球日记
我小的时候 8岁左右
When I was young, about 8 or so,
我请上帝来我家看棒球赛
I tried making friends with God
和他交个朋友
by inviting him to my house to watch the World Series.
他没来
He never showed.
可惜了 神父 我刚开始爽起来
Too bad, Father. I was just starting to enjoy myself.
如果你愿意我们明天可以继续 卡罗先生
We can do it again tomorrow if you like, Mr. Carroll.
没事吧 吉姆 疼吗
You okay, Jim? Does it hurt?
你想给他揉揉 佩德罗
You want to rub it for him, Pedro?
吉姆 算了吧 你拗不过他
Jim, give it a rest. You'll never beat him.
那人是个变态
The guy's a pervert.
你听见他说了吗
Did you hear him?
如果你愿意我们明天可以继续 卡罗先生
"We can do it again tomorrow if you like, Mr. Carroll."
我们翘课吧 走
Let's cut out of here. Come on.
# 我在游泳池里出生 #
# I was born in a pool #
# 他们让我妈站着 #
# They made my mother stand #
# 我溅到了那医生 #
# I spat on that surgeon #
# 和他颤抖的手 #
# And his trembling hand #
# 当我感受到光明 #
# When I felt the light #
# 比无聊还难受 #
# I was worse than bored #
# 我偷了医生的手术刀 #
# I stole a doctor's scalpel #
# 剪断了脐带 #
# And I slit the cord #
# 我曾是个天主教男孩 #
# I was a Catholic boy #
# 我从痛苦中重生 #
# I was redeemed through pain #
# 而并非欢乐 #
# Not through joy #
# 我早产了两个月 #
# I was two months early #
# 他们把我放进玻璃罩 #
# They put me under glass #
# 我朝其他孩子叫嚷 #
# I screamed and cursed their children #
# 当护士经过 #
# When the nurses passed #
# 我被当成了小偷 #
# I was convicted of theft #
# 当我从子宫里滑出 #
# As I slid from the womb #
# 他们把我直接拽了出来 #
# They led me straight from my mother #
# 带我进了坟墓 #
# To a cell in the tombs #
# 我曾是个天主教男孩 #
# I was a Catholic boy #
# 我从痛苦中重生 #
# Redeemed through pain #
# 而并非欢乐 #
# Not through joy #
# 他们饿了我几周 #
# They starved me for weeks #
# 以为教会了我害怕 #
# They thought they'd teach me fear #
# 我为狱友的梦想而活 #
# I fed on cellmates' dreams #
# 它给了我灵感 #
# It gave me fine ideas #
# 他们放了我的时候 #
# When they cut me loose #
# 我已经学到了很多 #
# The time had served me well #
# 我将在天堂里结盟 #
# I'd made allies in heaven #
# 在地狱里拉党 #
# Comrades in hell #
# 我曾是个天主教孩子 #
# I was a Catholic child #
# 血是红的 #
# The blood ran red #
# 血流成河 #
# The blood ran wild #
小混蛋 这是我的新...
Why, you little prick! This is my new...
糟了 快走 我吐在一个人身上了
Shit, guys, gotta get outta here. I threw up on somebody.
我会抓到你的
I'll get ya!
嘿
Hey!
我们四个对张伯伦怎么样
What about the four of us versus Wilt Chamberlain?
他一直是最棒的
He was the greatest of all time.
我们四个
Four of us?
你会做什么 佩德罗
What are you gonna do, Pedro?
趁他没注意的时候把他两个鞋带系一起
tie his shoes together when he ain't looking?
好吧... 那你们三个对张伯伦怎么样
All right... How'bout the three versus Wilt Chamberlain?
没问题
No problem.
你开玩笑吧 米奇
You're kidding, right, Mickey?
没啊 他不能同时看住我们仨
No. He can't cover all of us at the same time.
别错过我的跳投
You guys don't miss open jumpers.
我会抢到篮板的
And you know who will be there for the rebounds.
篮板 那家伙可有七英尺高
Rebounds? That freak is, like, 7 feet tall.
吉姆 谁的篮板我都能抢
Jim, I can rebound with anybody.
你除了吹牛
You're sniffing too much of that shit,
还会什么
that's what you're doing.
张伯伦能把我们都打败 就这样
Chamberlain would destroy all of us. End of story.
我们只需要运球
Alright. All we got to do is move the ball around.
不可能赢不了 你能和他说说吗
There's no way we don't win. Will you tell this kid?
米奇 我觉得你就能打败他
Hey, Mickey, I think you could beat him yourself.
你不需要我们
I don't think you need us.
完美的例子... 自信 我知道我能打败他
Perfect example... confidence. I know I could beat him.
看这个地方
Holy shit! Look at this place.
如果我们学校也这么漂亮
I tell you what, if our school was this nice,
我每周会多去几次
I'd go more than once a week.
就你 你压根就不识几个字
You? Yon can't even read.
我们今天要比赛 先生们
We got a game today, gentlemen.
谁准备好玩球了
Who's ready to play some roundball?
我说 谁准备好打球了
I said, who's ready to play some ball?
谁今天敢偷懒
You give me that laid-back,
不好好和大家配合
"I'm doing my own thing, Jack" attitude out there today,
我就让谁
and you're going to find yourself
坐在板凳上看比赛
watching the game from the bench.
别抽了... 影响发育
No smoking, lggy... stunts your growth.
你想和我一样强壮不
You want to be big and strong like me, don't you?
出去
Out.
别抽了
No smoking,
别在比赛前玩你的小鸟
and no pulling your peckers before a game.
史威夫帝 你干吗 我在拉屎 别烦我
Swifty, do you mind? I'm taking a dump. Get outta here!
有人死了吗
Something die in there?
在比赛的时候...
When we play our game...
佩德吐在他头上了 对吧
so Pedro vomits on his head, right?
头发上都是 流脖子里了
It goes all over his hair, trickles down his neck.
还流进他眼睛里 他抓狂了
Some gets in his eye. He went nuts
就是这样 相信我
Don't lie about it, either.Don't lie.
你们在干吗
What are you doing?
给鲍比签名
We're signing a ball for Bobby.
我能签吗
Can I sign?
可以
Yeah.
我们给你留着位置呢 孩子
"We're holding your spot for you, kid.
史威夫帝
Swifty."
好了
All right.
让我们为鲍比而战
This one's for Bobby.
来吧
All right.
有人比我们强大吗
Who's better than we are?
没有
Nobody!
去吧 做些热身
Alright! Go ahead. Do some warm-ups.
佩德 你负责
Pedro, you're in charge.
你是我的左右手
You're my eyes and ears.
嘿 吉姆 啊
Hey, Jim? Yeah?
你为鲍比做了件好事
That's a nice thing you're doing for Bobby.
谢谢 谢谢
Oh, thanks. Thanks.
看见纽琼了吗
You seen Neutron?
他好像在楼上
I think he's talking to a scout from Saint John's,
和圣约翰的球探说话
as a matter of fact, upstairs.
你想去大学篮球联赛打球 是吧
You want to play college ball, don't you?
是啊 我想去
Yeah. Someday, I hope. You know.
球探已经开始注意你了
Scouts are sniffing you out already.
他们喜欢年轻的
They like them young.
这样吧
I'll tell you what.
有时间你就过来
You come by sometime,
我们讨论一下那些学校
and we'll go over the schools together.
哦 好的
Yeah. All right.
可以叫个披萨 花一晚上的时间
Yeah. We'll get a pizza, and we'll make a night of it.
不过我最近晚上都挺忙的
Um... actually, my nights are kind of busy right now.
做作业是吧
Homework and all, huh?
对
Yeah. Yeah.
我们曾经是纽约最棒的天主教高中球队
We were the hottest Catholic high school team in New York City,
一路打到了决赛
on our way to the championship.
谁都不能阻拦我们
We felt like nothing could stop us.
马上就赢了
Yes! We're on our way.
We're on our way.
加油 加油
Let's go. Let's go.
抬起手 防守
Hands up. Show me some defense.
防守
Show me some defense.
抢得好 投球 投球
Good steal. Put it in. Put it in.
不错
All right. All right.
就这样
Way to go.
好样的 纽琼 对 对
All right, Neutron. Yes! Yes!
传球 吉姆
To the hole, Jim.
怎么回事
What's going on?
散开
Break it up!
打啊 打丫的
Come on. Hit him! Beat that motherfucker!
他刚才拉人
He fucking held me!
已经吹哨了
This dude blows the whistle...
慢点 慢点
Slow it down! Slow it down!
你在场上要有存在感
You got to have presence on the court...
像一只猎豹而不是只猩猩
presence like a cheetah rather than a chimp.
虽然都差不多
They both got it,
但猩猩得一直跳来跳去的
but chimpy got to jump his nuts around all day to get it.
害羞的猎豹只是冷静地移动
Shy cheetah just moves in total nonchalance
在他性感缓慢的阔步之间
a sec or two in his sexy, slow strut.
我 像猎豹一样打球
Me, I play like a cheetah.
加油 流浪者
Let's go, Rangers
加油
let's go!
加油 流浪者 加油
Let's go, Rangers, let's go!
就这样 胜利是我们的 我们就要赢了
You got it! It's ours. It's ours.
九 八
9, 8,
七
7,
六
6,
五
5,
四
4,
三
3,
二
2,
一
1!
耶 吉姆 糟糕
Yay, Jim! Oh, shit.
这是我的球队 我的球队
That's my team! That's my team!
只有两件事史威夫帝不让我们做...
There's only two things Swifty forbids...
说傻逼这个词
using the word "motherfucker"
和偷别的队的东西
and stealing from the other team,
只要他们是白人
as long as they're white.
冠军们吃了多少钱
How much for that group of winners over there?
一共三十四块九
It's $34.90.
三十四块九 对
$34.90? Yeah.
你们涨价了还是怎么着
Changed the prices or something?
没有
No.
我现在钱不够
I'm a little short.
帮个忙 我把手表留这里
Do me a favor. Here. Take my watch,
剩下的钱等会给你送过来
and I'll come back later with the rest of the money.
不行
No.
不行是什么意思
What do you mean, no?
抱歉 先生
I'm sorry, sir.
那些汉堡比你的表值钱
Those burgers are worth more than the watch is.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
不是说了一人吃一个汉堡吗
I told you one burger each, didn't I?
拜托
Come on, sir.
你又不是不知道我们一人吃八个才能吃饱
You know it takes at least eight of these to get filled up.
史威夫帝 我们可是大小伙子了
Yeah. C'mon, Swifty. We're growing boys.
大小伙子 我们他妈的饿死了
Growing boys? We're hungry motherfuckers.
有趣吗
Funny, huh?
我不送你们回家了
I'm not driving you guys home.
你们继续笑啊
How's that for laughs?
别这样 史威夫帝
C'mon, Swifty.
你们偷东西了 是不是
You ripped them off, didn't you?
还清了
We're even now.
史威夫帝 我们怎么回家啊
Swifty, come on. How are we going to get home?
自己看着办吧 白痴
Face the music, pricks.
我们怎么办 他们把门堵住了
What are we going to do? They got the door blocked off.
你怕这些小娘们
You afraid of these pussies?
我谁都不怕
I ain't afraid of anybody.
怎么了
What's the problem?
我只问你一次
I'm going to ask you this once. All right?
你偷我的东西在哪
Where's the stuff you stole from me?
你说什么
What are you talking about?
你别跟我这装傻
No, no, no. You're not going to fuck with me, all right?
有人从我的柜子里把我爸的戒指偷走了
Now, somebody stole my father's ring from my locker,
傻逼
motherfucker.
想被砍吗 过来啊
You want me to cut you? Is that what you want, there?
没问题
There's no problem here.
快走 快
Hey, guys! Let's get out of here, c'mon!
还敢叫人
You need a fucking army, huh?
快 快
Come on! Come on!
真漂亮 这是波波的
Oh. Nice. That from Bobo?
是他爸的戒指
That's his father's ring.
小伙子们 想玩玩嘛
Hey, fellas. Any of you looking for a date?
我 甜心
Yeah. Me, sweetheart.
去中央公园骑马
Little horsy ride in Central Park,
再吃顿烛光晚餐或是滚滚草地
maybe candlelight dinner or my good stuff?
直接吃甜点怎么样 宝贝
Why don't we skip right to dessert, huh, baby?
十五块钱
About $15?
十五块
Fifteen bucks?
我给你二十五美分 让佩德舔你的奶子
I'll give you a quarter. Let Pedro suck your tits.
干吗这么粗鲁啊
You don't have to be rude.
对不起啦
Oh, I'm sorry.
你呢 帅哥
How about you, handsome, huh?
十五块钱 来一次
You got $15... for a little head?
戴安 你看我像会给钱的人吗
Diane, do I look like I need to pay for it?
像
Yeah...
你会给的
you do.
如果值得的话
If it's worth it.
吉米
Jimmy...
吉米 我知道你想要 亲爱的
Jimmy, I know you want some, honey.
十五块 我保证让你爽 宝贝
$15. I'll do you so good you'll never forget it, baby.
再商量一下
Bargain from there.
你们说呢 你们要吗 我们四个
What do you say, guys? You want to do it? All four of us?
行
It's a deal.
我们四个一起
All four of us.
我就剩这点儿了 戴安
Aw, shit. This is all I got, Diane.
赶紧滚 走开
Get out of here. Beat it.
去你妈的
Yeah, fuck you!
嗑药的 那破玩意有什么好的
Fucking dopehead. You see what that shit does to you?
说到嗑药的
Wow. Speaking of dopeheads,
佩德他妈又在那拉客呢吧
is that Pedro's mother over there slinging her wares again?
真是
It is!
佩佩 你去哪
Hey, Peepee, where you going?
你为什么总那么混啊
Why do you have to be such an asshole all the time, huh?
这只小鞋有什么好哭的
Why is the little shoe crying anyway?
他妈是双跑鞋 他爸是双拖鞋
His mother's a sneaker. His father's a loafer.
总有人得有点跟儿啊
Somebody's got to be a heel.
吉姆 你去哪
Jim, where you going?
嘿 吉姆
Hey, Jim!
吉姆
Jim.
嘿 哥们
Hey. Hey, man.
怎么样
What's up?
认不出我的新发型了
You don't recognize me with my new hairdo?
很不错 我喜欢
It's nice. It's nice. I like it.
怎么样了
What's going on?
- 还好吗  - 不错
- How are you?  - Good.
看看
Wow. Look at that.
喜欢吗
You like it?
等你出院
Yeah, I'll tell you what. When you get out of here,
我们都把头剃了 看着会像光头党的
we'll all shave our heads and look like a gang of skinheads.
说定了
It's a deal.
好
All right.
我给你带了点东西
I got something for you here.
谢谢
Yeah.
每个队员的名字都在上面
Everyone on the team.
看这... 史威夫帝都签了
Look right here... even Swifty signed it.
谢谢
Thanks, man.
记得我在河滨公园的扣篮吗
You remember when I dunked on that spade in Riverside Park?
你总能跳得很高
You always had good ups.
嗯
Yeah.
给你看个东西 等会
Oh. I got something to show you. Hold on.
什么啊
What?
佩得从一个女人的包里偷的
Pedro got these out of some lady's purse.
- 她和驴做呢  - 哦 天哪
- She's doing it with a donkey.  - Oh, Jesus!
看看它的阴茎 你看啊
Look at that schlong. Look at that one.
我超越了你的记录
Oh, I beat your record.
你做了几次
How many times you choke it?
七次
Seven times.
扯
Bullshit.
七次
Seven times.
我妈以为我一直在感冒
My mom thinks I have a cold year-round
因为满屋子都是手纸
because of all the tissues around the house.
想要的话你可以留着
You can keep those if you want.
那群护士给我体内灌了一堆垃圾
They're pumping so much junk in me,
我现在瘦得皮包骨头
I can't even get a decent chubby.
我有个主意
I got an idea.
快 我们走
Come on. Let's go.
去哪
Where we going?
不能再让你待这儿了 快点
I'm getting you out of this place, man. C'mon!
你疯了吗 我哪都去不了
What are you, crazy, man? I can't go anywhere.
走吧
Here you go.
我三岁就认识鲍比了 他是我最好的朋友
I've known Bobby since I was 3. He's my best friend.
他曾是篮球队最优秀的队员
He was the best player on our basketball team.
两年前 他得了白血病
Two years ago, he got leukemia.
他一直在与病魔做斗争
He keeps fighting it off.
我知道鲍比会没事的
I know Bobby's going to beat it.
他从未被打败过
He could beat anything.
小心点
Watch!
吉姆 你要杀了我啊
Jim, you're going to kill me, man.
你要敢放手 我发誓
If you let go, I swear...
我发誓我会杀了你的
I swear I'll kill you, man.
看着点
Watch the bump!
夜生活都去哪了
What the hell happened to forty deuce?
上次我来这
Last time I was here,
那影院还在上映性爱机器人2呢
that theater was playing Sperminator II.
对 我记得
Oh, yeah. I remember that.
整个街区
No, man. This whole block has been done over
已经被这些新艺术家翻新了
by all these new artists.
还不错 是吧
It's pretty cool, huh?
嗯
Yeah.
他们应该把你的东西放这
They should put your stuff up there.
没错
Yeah. Right.
你还在写东西吗
Still scribbling stuff in that notebook of yours, ain't you?
当然了
Of course.
给我带来了吗
You bring anything for me?
读的东西
What, like to read?
还能是吃的
No, like to eat.
你说呢
What do you think?
有这个 没什么好看的
Yeah. I mean, I got this, but it's not a big deal.
实话说 我都不记得写过这个了
I don't even remember writing it, to tell you the truth.
好 让我来评论一下
Yeah, Yeah. I'll be the judge of this.
小孩子玩弹珠
"Little kids shoot marbles
弹弓打到了太阳上
"where branches break the sun
落下万丈光芒 我只想纯洁下去
"into graceful shafts of light. I just want to be pure.
我只想纯洁下去
I just want to be pure.
来吧
All right.
# 生活啊 #
# What a life #
只有亲眼所见才能真正兴奋起来 对吧 鲍比
Nothing like the real thing to float your boat, huh, Bobby?
# 生活啊 #
# What a life #
# 不知在何处 不知在何时 #
# Didn't know where, didn't know when... #
不错啊
That's nice.
# 说要走 学会成长 #
# Said that I'll go... go learn #
# 挥挥手 等我回来 #
# Put up my hand, wait my turn #
# 但我从未归去 我要大喊 #
# But it never comes, I have to shout out #
# 那就是生活 #
# That's life #
# 那就是生活的意义 #
# And that's what it's all about #
# 经过了安逸与冲突 #
# So through the comfort and the strife #
# 生活啊 #
# What a life... #
让我出去 吉姆
Get me out of here, Jim.
你说什么啊
What are you talking about, man?
这个主意太蠢了
This was a stupid idea.
我不舒服
I don't feel so good.
那等表演完了行吗
Well, can we wait till the end of the show?
你听见我说什么没有
Did you hear what I said?
我说把我他妈的推出去
I said get me the hell out of here!
嘿 鲍勃
Hey, Bob, man...
我真的很抱歉 下次 我们去别的地方
I'm really sorry, you know? Next time, we'll go somewhere...
没有下次了 吉姆
Ain't gonna be no next time, Jim.
我喜欢这样
I love it this way...
把脚放在发软的沥青上
my feet against the tar, which is soft from the spring heat,
微风吹过你的身体
the slight breeze that runs across your entire body,
特别是胯下
especially your crotch.
在星空下光着身子感觉很强大
You feel an incredible power being naked under a dome of stars
整个城市的人都穿戴整齐
while a giant city is dressed,
车水马龙 穿梭在你的指缝间
dodging cars all around you five flights down.
这个时候我什么都不想
I don't think of anything while I'm doing the actual tugging,
尤其是以往在家里
least of all the heavy sex fantasies
冒出的性幻想
I have to resort to indoors.
只有我的裸体和星星喘息着
Just my own naked self and the stars breathing down,
很美好
and it's beautiful.
年轻的时候时间过得真的很快
Time sure flies when you're young and jerking off.
夏令营职务
"Camp summer position.
司机... 出租车
Driver... taxi."
那也许不错
Hey, that might be good.
你今年夏天就能拿到驾照了
You could get your license this summer.
对 妈 听着不错
Oh, yeah, Mom. That sounds really great.
找个工作吧
Hey, get your own job,
如果今年夏天找不到
and if you don't get it this summer,
你就跟我去饭店工作
you're coming to work with me at the hotel.
妈 拜托 你干吗这么担心
Mom, please. Why are you so worried about this?
我管你要过钱吗
Do I even ask you for money?
我不是担心钱
No. I'm not worried about the money.
你得有点责任感了
I want you to have responsibility.
我不想让你满纽约大街得跑
I don't want you running around the streets of New York.
浪费时间是恶魔的行径 吉姆
Idle time is the devil's plaything, Jim.
恶魔的行径
The devil's plaything, huh?
做我第一本书的名字不错
That might be a cool title for my first book.
谢谢 真不错
Thanks! That's good.
你说什么呢 你在写什么
What are you talking about? What are you writing?
这个
Here.
我不是很饿
Ma, I'm not really that hungry this morning, alright?
那也得吃点东西 我知道...
Come on. You got to eat something. I know...
你去哪儿
Where you going?
去打球
I'm going to shoot some hoops.
有时我感觉有东西在追我
Sometimes I feel like something's chasing me,
某个屋顶上的怪物
like there's some whacko on a roof somewhere
随时都能掐死我
who could snuff me out at any moment.
我真的很害怕 我还有时间去完成
And I feel this horrible fear. Will I have time to finish
那些没写出来的诗吗
the poems breaking loose in my head?
嘿 白鬼
Hey, white boy,
准备好被我打败了吗
you ready for your beating?
别让你的嘴给你惹事
Don't let your mouth
给你惹事
get you into something your ass can't handle.
给你投个球看看
I'll shoot you for it.
你就这一招儿
So it's going to be like that, huh?
我
I...
不这么想
don't think so.
你进了
All right, so you made one.
不错 你进了个球
Big deal. You made one shot.
再来一个
Make another.
# 这些天感觉自己被套牢了 #
# The days are muzzled in a vibe #
# 我在时间中游荡 #
# I swing back from time to time #
# 这有辆殷红色的卡玛洛 #
# There's a Camaro, rusty red #
# 我所有的好友都开过 #
# That all my best friends drive in #
# 闻到夏天的气味了吗 #
# Can you smell the summer air? #
# 带我到有光亮的地方去 #
# Take me where they left the light on #
# 越来越近 马上到达 #
# Getting close, almost there #
# 如果那银色的徽章 #
# If that fuzzy silver badge #
# 不向我们致敬 #
# Don't greet us there #
# 我头晕 我要... #
# My head's dizzy, and I'm taking... #
吉姆 比分是多少 快 我们该走了
Yo, Jim! What's the score? Come on. We got to go.
他们没计分
They don't keep score in this game.
他们没记分 吉姆 快啊 太阳快下山了
They don't score? Jim, come on. We're losing the sun.
他在那装聋子 用我暴揍他一顿么
He's being a dick. You want me to put a charge in his ass?
等着
Whatch this.
看 看这...
Oh, look it, right here...
吉姆的秘密日记
Jim's secret diary he's always writing in.
他肯定写我的坏话了
Bet you he wrote some shit about me.
在这
Oh, right here.
春天... 米奇
"Spring... Mickey."
嘿 我在这 吉姆说
Hey, there I am, Jim says.
米奇拿出一瓶碳酸饮料
"Mickey takes out a bottle of carbonic cleaning fluid
让我们都闻一下
and suggests we do a little sniffing to get high."
米奇 你干吗呢
Mickey, what are you doing?
铃声在我耳边回荡
"Bells ringing through my ears,
微弱的光亮穿过我眼前
little lights flashing through my eyes."
米奇 放下
Mickey, put that down, all right?
我想象自己
"I pictured myself
在黑河中划着小船
"paddling across a river with black water,
但船一直在后退
"only the canoe was going backwards instead of forwards,
云朵有了表情
"with clouds that had faces.
大笑 幽灵般 奇幻屋里的笑声
Laughing, spooky, fun-house laughs..."
还给我 这是什么玩意
Give it back, alright? What is that shit?
你怎么老这么烦人啊 米奇
Why do you have to be such a schmuck, Mickey?
你说什么啊
What are you talking about?
别再碰我的本子 这是隐私
Don't you ever touch that again. It's private.
你有病吧
What's your problem?
对不起
I'm... I'm sorry.
他写我了 还不让我看 天
He's writing about me, I can't read about it? Jesus!
嘿 吉姆 快 我们要走了
Hey, Jim, come on. We're gone.
有辆出租
Yo, we got a cab!
司机
Hey, cabby! Hey, swami!
小莎士比亚
So, Shakespeare,
还打不打了
you going to finish the game?
雷吉 你知道比赛永远没有结束的时候
C'mon, Reggie, you know this game never ends.
回见吧
See you later, all right?
每个小群体都有个游戏
Every crowd has its little games
来证明你是不是有种
to prove if you're a punk or not.
我在泽西的表哥玩胆小鬼的游戏
My cousin in Jersey plays chickie,
两辆车以八十公里的时速
which is two cars heading towards each other
相向行驶
at about 80 miles per hour.
先闪开的司机 就是胆小鬼
First driver to swerve out of the way is, of course, chicken.
在布鲁克林
In Brooklyn,
他们让你把点燃的烟戳胳膊上
they make you press a lit cigarette into your arm
一直到它烧到过滤嘴那里
and have it burn all the way down to the filter
不能有一点畏缩
without the slightest flinch.
我们曼哈顿的男孩
Us, Manhattan boys,
我们从悬崖上跳进哈林河
we jump off cliffs into the Harlem River,
其实有点恶心
which is literally shitty,
因为每天都有半吨的下水道垃圾
because half a million toilets
都会排到这里
flush into it every day.
我把衣服都拿上来了
Hey, y'all, I carried the clothes up,
我可不想再拿下去了
but I ain't carrying them down.
佩佩 这是你
Peepee, this is you...
三十三磅 随风消逝
all 33 pounds of you, gone with the wind.
这里好高啊
Wow. That's a long way down.
有什么新鲜的
Devil's toe is no big deal.
我们都玩过N多次了
We've all done it a million times.
我没玩过
I never done it.
没有吗
You never did it?
佩得 你什么都没玩过
Pedro, you never do nothing.
你知道谁玩这个最强吗
You know who was awesome on this rock?
鲍比 他敢从这里后空翻下去
Bobby. That kids would do back flips off this rock.
米奇
Hey, Mickey.
干吗
What?
别说得他好像死了似的
Don't talk about him like he's dead.
他没死
He's not dead.
该死 游轮来了 看
Oh, shit! There goes the circle line. Check it out.
圆月亮
Full moon!
看看啊
Hey, circle this!
我要跳了 看着 看着...
Hey, I'm going. Watch out, watch out...
我要让你看看该怎么做
I'm going to show you how to do it.
跳得不错
That was a good jump.
他疯了
Oh, he's nuts.
我要走下去
Hey, I'm going to walk down.
你说什么呢 你不能走下去
What you talking about? You can't walk down.
这没有下去的路
There's no way to walk down.
我不要跳
I ain't jumping.
佩得 你的衣服都在下面
Pedro, your clothes are down there.
你怎么拿衣服啊
How you gonna get your clothes?
你想一天都光着身子么
You going to walk around naked all day?
佩得 你要是不跳的话 米奇会嘲笑你的
Pedro, if you don't jump, Mickey's going to tease you so bad
你就赶紧跳下去吧
You might as well just jump and get it over with.
快点
Feel better.
管它呢
What the hell, right?
糟了
shit...
佩得
Pedro!
糟了 糟了
Bad form. Bad form.
哦... 天
Oh... My God!
他没事吧
Oh, shit. Is he all right?
佩得 你没事吧
Pedro, you all right?
准备好了吗
You ready?
嗯
Yeah.
别告诉别人
Listen, don't tell the other guys,
等我们回去之后 我给你准备了一个惊喜
but when we leave here, I got a surprise for you.
是什么啊
Tell me what it is.
惊喜 相信我吧
It's a surprise. Trust me, all right?
别碰我
Ouch, don't mess around, man...
准备好了吗 好了吗
Alright, you ready? Come on! You ready?
跳吧 数三下 就跳
Let's jump. On three. Ready?
一
1,
二
2,
三
3.
快 走吧
Come on. Let's go.
怎么样 你好吗
What's up, Manny? How you doing?
很好 谢谢 先生
Fine. Thank you, sir.
这是我朋友吉姆
This is my friend Jim.
你好吗
How you doing?
真不敢相信 我竟然撞石头上了
I can't believe I hit my head on that rock.
疼死了
It's killing me.
吉姆 这是温基
Jim, um, this is Winkie.
嗨 你好吗
Hi. How you doing?
很好
Good.
这位是...
And this...
布兰基
this is Blinkie.
嗨 嗨
Hi. Hi.
# 我在桥下 #
# I lost my heart #
# 迷失了自己 #
# Under the bridge #
# 那个小姑娘... #
# That little girl... #
我看过你打球 吉姆
I've seen you play ball, Jim.
你打得不错
You're a very beautiful player.
非常从容
Very zen.
# 我呻吟 #
# And now I moan #
# 我大喊 #
# And now I holler #
# 她不会知道 #
# She'll never know #
# 我发现了什么 #
# Just what I found #
# 那个蓝眼睛姑娘 #
# That blue-eyed girl #
这个能让你变成超人
lt'll make you fuck like Superman.
# 她再也不说话了 #
# She said no more #
比子弹还快
Faster than a speeding bullet...
# 变成了个蓝眼睛的妓女 #
# Became blue-eyed whore... #
比火车头还有劲
More powerful than a locomotive...
# 随着流水 #
# Down by the water #
# Down by the water... #
比...
Able to, um...
我想不出别的词了
I can't think of anything with a single bound.
# 再见到她 #
# See her again #
# See her again... #
你有没有套套
Do you have any protection?
有
Yeah.
这个螺纹能带来更多的快感
This one's, uh, ribbed for extra pleasure.
你还等什么
So what are you waiting for?
嗯
What do you mean?
把衣服脱了
Take off your clothes.
能先把灯关了吗
could we shut off the lights first?
# 小鱼 大鱼 #
# Little fish, big fish #
# 水中游 #
# Swimming in the water #
# 回来吧 #
# Come back here, man #
# 把我女儿给我 #
# Give me my daughter #
# 小鱼 大鱼 #
# Little fish, big fish #
# 水中游 #
# Swimming in the water #
今早白色的轮船消失在巨浪之中
White ship disappears in the wave machine this morning.
你安静地闭上眼睛
Your eyes got shut with secret chains
枕边的军队也消停了下来...
that pillow armies eventually set free...
像是小马跑过玩具沙漠
like soft horses through toy deserts.
我喜欢这栋楼
I love this mansion,
虽然有太多窗户...
though it's too many windows...
需要在早上打开
to open halfway each morning...
在晚上关上
to close halfway each night.
我看着他的尸体
I looked at his body,
那是我第一次面对死亡
and it was death for the first time.
他的脸瘦削苍老
His face was thin and wrinkled, almost apelike.
他的头发 只是头皮上几块灰色的片
His hair, just gray patches on his scalp.
他看上去有六十了 但事实上他才十六岁
He looked 60 years old, and he was 16.
我不敢相信他变得这么瘦...
Couldn't believe how skinny he was...
比在医院时还要瘦很多
much skinnier than he was in the hospital.
就好像是把你认识的某人的骨架
It was like having the skeleton of someone you knew
摆在你面前一样
put right in front of you.
我头晕 像是
I felt dazed, like
刚看了四小时长的晦涩电影
I'd just come out of a four-hour movie I didn't understand.
我不断想到他的脸
I kept thinking about his face...
和死亡
and death...
这整件事就是个骗局
what a cheat the whole thing was.
你们记得那年万圣节
Hey, you guys remember that Halloween
鲍比装了一袋子狗屎
when Bobby filled that paper bag with dog shit,
点着了之后放在邓恩神父门口
lit it on fire and put it outside Father Dunne's door,
而我们就藏在垃圾桶后面吗
and we all hid behind the dumpster?
记得
Yeah.
我清楚记得邓恩神父
I could picture Father Dunne
走出来 踩到狗屎
comming outside, stepping on that shit.
记得他在厕所里
Picture him in the john
像这样把狗屎从鞋上弄下来
scraping the shit off his shoe like this.
你觉得这样他就上不了天堂了吗
You think that'll keep him out of heaven?
开什么玩笑 上帝自己
Are you kidding? Jesus Christ himself
都会笑的 那实在是太搞了
would have laughed at that. It was hilarious!
还有那次开会
What about the time at the formal
鲍比和玛丽·安在
when Bobby got caught in the bathroom
厕所被抓到
with Mary Ann Dugan
之后麦克纳帝进来把他抽了一顿
and McNulty came in and busted him?
他还说 "神父 我发誓
He was, like, "Father, I swear.
我们什么也没做"
We weren't doing anything."
那时候她脸上还有
Meanwhile she's got a giant wad of cum
一大滩精液往下流
hanging off her face.
那孩子就是个混球
I tell you, that kid was definitely a pisser.
今天看见他有点古怪
It was weird seeing him today, man.
他全身都是皱纹
He was all shriveled up and wrinkled.
像我爷爷似的
He looked like my grandfather.
不过
I'll tell you what, though.
他当时太痛苦了
That kid was in so much pain,
还是早点死了比较好
it's better off he died.
你他妈怎么知道的 米奇
How the hell would you know, Mickey?
你去看过他吗
Did you go and visit him?
你们谁去看过他
Any of you guys go and visit him?
都他妈的闭嘴
All right. Then shut the fuck up.
吉姆 我哥哥的女友在公园里
Hey, Jim. Look at my brother's girlfriend in the park.
坐着吃三明治
She's sitting there, eating a sandwich.
之后 她被杀了
Next thing you know, she's shot in the head.
她死了 全完了
She's dead. It's over.
小泰迪·瑞希尔呢
What about little Teddy Rayhill?
说得好
Perfect example.
记得那天晚上他在楼顶
Remember that night he was up on the roof,
嗑药嗑得很嗨
and he was doing poppers, having a great time,
笑疯了
laughing his ass off
然后他开始往后退...
He started walking backwards...
咚的一声 从他妈的楼顶上掉下去了
Boom! He fell right off the goddamn roof.
这都是注定的 不是吗
It was meant to be, right?
去你妈的
Fuck that, you guys!
鲍比是这儿最牛逼的人 你们知道吗
Bobby was the best fucking guy around, you know that?
你们呢 一群白痴
What are you, a bunch of idiots?
你们懂什么
You don't even understand, do you?
吉姆 你没事吧
Jim, you all right?
也许你该和神父聊聊
Listen, maybe you should talk to one of the priests.
也许... 也许他们能帮你
I don't know. Maybe... Maybe they can help you out.
帮我
Help me out?
我才不会向他们请求帮助
I wouldn't ask one of those cocksuckers for directions.
知道么
You know what?
你们都给我听着
You guys need to lighten the fuck up, all right?
过去的事就过去了
Let bygones be fucking bygones.
这该死的世界
Shitty fucking world.
你得活在当下 知道吗
Live life to the fucking fullest. You know what I mean?
总会有倒霉的事
Shit happens, man.
总他妈的会有倒霉的事
Shit fucking happens.
走吧
Come on. Let's go.
吉姆 走吧
Jim, come on.
你慢慢长大了
You're growing up,
雨水似乎还挂在树上
and rain sort of remains on the branches of a tree
总有一天会统治这个世界
that will someday rule the earth.
下雨很好
And that's good that there's rain.
清洗掉多日来的阴霾
Clears the month of your sorry rainbow expressions.
也将街道洗刷干净
And it clears the streets of the silent armies
所以我们可以跳舞了
so we can dance.
# 泰德十二岁吸胶毒 #
# Ted sniffing glue He was 12 years old #
# 从东2-9座的楼顶摔死了 #
# Fell from the roof on east 2-9 #
# 凯西十一岁开始混 #
# Cathy was 11 when she pulled the plug #
# 二十六片药丸和一瓶酒 #
# 26 reds and a bottle of wine #
# 鲍比十四岁得了白血病 #
# Bobby had leukemia, 14 years old #
# 死的时候像是六十五岁了 #
# He looked like 65 when he died #
# 他是我的朋友 #
# He was a friend of mine #
# 那些人都死了死了 #
# Those are people who died, died #
# 他们都是我的朋友 #
# They were all my friends #
# 他们死了 #
# They just died #
# 那些人都死了死了 #
# Those are people who died, died #
# 他们都是我死去的朋友 #
# They were all my friends and they died #
我有没有讲过我第一次吸海洛因的事
Did I ever tell you about the first time I did heroin?
我去了佩德家的地下室
I went down to Pedro's basement.
打靶场的储藏室里
All sorts of characters
有各路货色
were in the storage-room shooting gallery.
我开始只是想吸一包
I was just going to sniff a bag,
但有个人说
but a guy says,
"如果你要吸 那还不如用抽的
"If you're going to sniff, might as well pop it,
如果你要用抽的 还不如用静脉注射"
and if you're going to pop it, might as well mainline."
我怕针头
I was scared of needles,
但我妥协了
but I gave in.
就像是有一股暖流穿过我的身体
It was like a long heat wave through my body.
所有疼痛 悲伤
Any ache or pain or sadness
和负罪感都被冲走了
or guilty feeling was completely flushed out.
妈 我没心情
Look, Ma, I'm not in the mood
听你的廉价心理学
for your dime-store psychology, all right?
能让我自己待着吗
Could you just please leave me alone?
我有点难受
I got a little sick, all right?
我们不能这样活着 吉姆
We're not going to live like this, Jim.
我们不能这样活着
We're not going to live like this.
我警告你 我告诉你
I'm warning you! I'm telling you.
哦 妈
Oh, God, Mom.
你总是在警告我 不是吗
You're always warning me, aren't you?
没完没了 总在我耳边啰嗦
Blah, blah, blah. You're always in my fucking ear.
你什么都不懂
Blah, blah, blah. You don't know anything.
你说什么
What are you talking about?
去擦厕所吧 该干什么干什么
Go clean toilets or whatever the hell it is you do.
等你干完了 也把我处理了
When you're done, clean this one.
别这样说话
Don't talk like that!
你到底怎么了
What's the matter with you?
妈 知道吗...
Gee whiz, Ma, you know...
我们应该经常谈谈心
we got to have these heart-to-heart talks more often.
真的有好处
They're really good for us.
我不认识你了
I don't know you.
我不相信这是你 吉姆
I don't believe this is you, Jim.
别这样 吉姆 我都不认识你了
Please, Jim. I don't know who you are.
我知道 我原来是个乖孩子...
Yeah, I know. I was such a good little boy, right...
有很大的潜力 是吧
with such potential, wasn't that it?
你是想说这些吗
Is that what you're going to say?
吉姆 你怎么了
Oh, Jim. What's happening?
Jim, what's happening?
开始 只是周六晚上的消遣
First, it's a Saturday-night thing,
感觉不错 自己好像成了个暴徒或者摇滚明星
and you feel cool, like a gangster or a rock star.
只是为了消磨下时间
It's just something to kill the boredom, you know?
他们管这叫小爱好
They call it a chippie, a small habit.
你爱上了这种感觉 所以每周二也吸了
It feels so good, you start doing it on Tuesdays,
然后是每周四
then Thursdays.
于是你染上了毒瘾
Then it's got you.
街上的每个小混混都说
Every wise-ass punk on the block says
他们不会染上毒瘾
it won't happen to them,
但他们会的
but it does.
快去
Go do it!
我不去 怎么老是我去
I ain't doing it. I always do it!
我去 我去
I'll do it. I'll do it.
打扰了 夫人
Excuse me, ma'am.
能告诉我怎么去地铁最快吗
Could you tell me the fastest way to the subway?
最近的是二号线
Yeah. That's the "B" train.
在这个路口左转
Go to this corner and make a left.
就在那儿
It's right there.
你干什么 放开 放开
What are you doing? Let go! Let go!
还给我
Let go of that!
哦 天啊
Oh, my God! What? Oh!
救命 不 不 你在干吗
Help! No! No! What are you doing?
走吧
Let's go!
快点
Come on!
我今天不想进去
I don't feel like going in today.
神父 我今天不进去可以吗
Father, is it all right if I don't go in today?
为什么 你怕什么
Why? What are you scared of?
没什么 我就是不太想去
Nothing. I just don't feel like it, that's all.
我想你比任何人都需要忏悔
I imagine you have more to confess than anybody here.
倾诉你自己吧
Unburden yourself.
保佑我 神父 我有罪
Bless me, Father, for I have sinned.
我已经四个月没来忏悔过了
It's been about four months since my last confession.
说吧 孩子
Yes, my son?
我不知道从何说起 神父
Well, I don't know where to start, Father.
你有没有滥用耶稣基督的圣名
Have you taken the name of Jesus Christ in vain?
有 我有
Yeah. Yeah, I have.
你对父母不敬了吗
Have you disrespected your mother and father?
是的
Uh-huh.
你欺骗或偷盗朋友的东西了吗
Have you stolen or cheated your fellow man?
是的 但我并不引以为傲
Yeah, but I'm not proud of it.
你有没有肮脏的想法
Have you had impure thoughts
或者参与了肮脏的行为
or engaged in impure deeds?
神父 你不明白
Oh, Father, you have no idea.
你还有什么
Is there something else
想用自己的话说的吗
that you want to tell me in your own words?
这些坏事我干尽了
I've done all kinds of crazy shit.
等等 神父
Oh, excuse me, Father.
操 我...
Fuck, I'm s...
上帝 我的嘴真脏
Christ, I have a dirty mouth.
我很抱歉
Look, I'm... I'm sorry about that.
你继续吧
Will you just go on?
十遍《圣母经》
10 Hail Marys,
五遍《我们的神父》
five Our Fathers.
什么意思
What do you mean?
就这样了
And that's it?
这就是我的惩罚
That's my punishment?
你知道吗
You know someone?
我朋友鲍比 他是最强的
My friend Bobby, he was the best,
但他死了
and he's dead.
糟透了 真的糟透了
This sucks! You know that? This really sucks.
这不公平 神父
It's not fair, Father.
你在流鼻涕
Your nose is running,
肚子绞痛
your stomach cramps,
你的腿感觉就像
your legs feel like they've played
互相连着打了六场大仗
six straight games on top of each other,
你脑子里总有一种声音
and the voice is always there in the back of your head...
"再吸一次 然后就戒了"
"Just one more time. then we'll stop."
快接球 快接球
Quick to the ball. Quick to the ball.
两只手 好的 伊格内修斯
Two hands. Good, Ignatius.
好 快接球 两只手 跟上
Good. Good. Quick to the ball. Two hands. Right behind you.
教练 我能去趟厕所吗
Sir, all right if I use the bathroom, Coach?
吉姆 你怎么和女人一样麻烦
Jim, you got a bladder like a woman.
加油 继续
Let's go. Again.
跟上他
There we go. Right behind him.
Right behind him.
快接球 两只手 两只手
Quick to the ball. Two hands. Two hands.
吉姆
Jim?
我以为你撒尿呢
I thought you were taking a piss.
哦
Oh.
你每次训练都来这干吗
What are you doing in here every practice?
你在等我吗 吉姆
Have you been waiting for me, Jim?
是在暗示我吗
Giving me some kind of a signal?
你说什么啊 史威夫帝
What are you talking about, Swifty?
别装了
Don't act surprised.
把钱拿走
Put the money away.
不够多
You want more?
给
Here.
让我做吧
Just let me do it.
你给我滚蛋
Get the fuck out of my face!
别激动 吉姆
Take it easy, Jim.
你不能怪我
You can't blame me for trying.
我错了 行吧
I made a mistake, all right?
假装什么都没发生吧
Let's just pretend it never happened.
我们还会像原来一样
Things will go back to exactly how they were before.
成吗
Okay?
成吗 给 拿着钱吧
Okay? Here, keep the money.
拿着钱
Keep the money.
别告诉别人 好吗
Just don't tell anybody, all right?
好 去告诉他们
Good. Tell anybody you want!
没有人会相信你这个吸毒的小子
Nobody's going to believe a drughead like you, anyway.
你以为我们不知道你干了什么吗
You think we don't know what you've been doing?
把钱给我
Give me the fucking money
快滚
and get the fuck out of here.
滚蛋 快滚
Get the fuck Get the fuck out here!
快点 给我滚
Come on! Get out of here!
你想戒了 真的
And you want to stop. You really do.
但这就像个梦
But it's like a dream.
一个醒不了的梦
You can't stop dreams.
他们变幻莫测 恣意发展
They move in crazy pieces, any way they want to,
突然 你变成万能的了
and suddenly, you're capable of anything.
不
No!
醒醒 卡罗先生 看看几点了
Wake up, Mr. Carroll! It's later than you think.
好吧
Oh. All right!
我想兴奋一下 好啊
I need a lift. All right.
你那有什么
What do you got?
三种药 哪种是迷幻药
Three different pills. Which are the ups?
我没问 我以为你们知道呢
I never asked. I thought one of youse would know.
太好了
Oh, great.
我们像药剂师么
We look like pharmacists?
我不知道吃哪个
I don't know what to take.
吃哪个
What do we take?
给我看看
Let me see.
黑的和红的是迷幻药
The blacks and the reds are the ups.
我觉得是粉色的
I think the pink ones are the ups.
为什么
Why?
我把粉色和轻飘飘联系在一起
'Cuz I associate pink with lightness, you know?
黑色的看起来会让你屁股开花
The black ones seem like they'd knock you on your ass.
可能是掉了色的速可眠
They might be faded seconals.
不是掉色的
No, they're not faded.
掉色的是黏的 这些不黏
They'd be sticky. They're not.
胡扯
That's bullshit.
操你妈 你说什么
Fuck your mother. My what?
行了 冷静点
All right! Calm down.
别再提我妈
Don't ever talk about my mother.
否则我扭断你的脖子
I swear to God, I'll break your neck.
不会了 什么
Don't ever. What?
好了 把你帽子给我
Come on! Alright! Give me your hat.
还得打比赛呢
We got a game to play, alright?
给我点吧
Just give me something.
嗨 纽琼
Hi, Neutron.
我去问他
Let me ask him.
纽琼 你知道哪些是迷幻药吗
Neutron, you know which ones are the ups?
这里有三种
Now we have three kinds.
你得在史威夫帝进来之前
I think you should put that shit away
把这些垃圾藏起来
before Swifty comes in here.
你装什么正经啊
Why you acting like such a square ass?
去你的 米奇
Screw you, Mickey.
去你的 假正经
Screw you, too, Tough guy. Man.
我要吃黑色的
I'm just going to take the black.
你确定吗
You sure?
你有什么更好的主意吗
Mm-hmm. You got a better idea?
没 你猜的和我一样 吉姆
Nope. Your guess is as good as mine, Jimbo.
就今天了 要抢五十个篮板
It's on today. 50 rebounds.
好
Good.
上场吧
Come on. Let's go.
我现在是你朋友了
I'm your friend now, right?
想让我再扇你吗
What, I got to smack you again, c'mon!
带上你的跟屁虫
Yeah, take your little rat with you.
你干吗 怎么了
What's up, man? Hey, what's up?
你干吗这样
Why are you acting like that?
你知道为什么
You know what's wrong.
原来是兴奋起来打打球
Used to be about getting high and playing basketball.
现在只想兴奋了
Now it's just about getting high with you.
你在自毁前程 吉姆
You're blowing it, Jim.
你凭什么教育我 纽琼
Oh, come on. I don't need to hear this from you, Neutron.
我当然可以 吉姆 听着 吉姆
Yeah, you do, Jim! Listen, no, Jim!
我很为你骄傲
I'm really proud of you, man.
没事的 你看起来不错
Everything's cool. You look great.
我们NBA见
I'll see you in the NBA.
# 风雨中的骑士 #
# Riders on the storm #
# 走进了我们出生的房子 #
# Into this house we're born #
# 走进了把我们抛弃的世界 #
# Into this world we're thrown #
# 像是没了骨头的狗 #
# Like a dog without a bone #
# 我们都是孤独的 #
# In fact we're all alone #
# 风雨中的骑士 #
# Riders on the storm #
# 公路上有个杀手 #
# There's a killer on the road #
# 他的大脑像蛤蟆一样蠕动 #
# His brain is squirming like a toad #
# 度个长假 #
# Take a long holiday #
# 让孩子们去玩耍 #
# Let your children play #
# 如果你载了他一程 #
# If you give this man a ride #
# 甜蜜的一家就会死光 #
# Sweet family will die #
# 公路上的杀手 #
# Killer on the road #
# 耶 #
# Yeah ##
找到了吗
Did you find it?
没 神父 很干净 这里没有毒品
No, Father. It's clean. There's no drugs in there.
谢谢你 警官
Thank you, Officer.
我说了我们什么都没有
I told you we didn't have nothing.
你们以为自己很聪明吗
You boys think you're awfully smart, don't you?
留校查看一周
Well, you're both suspended for a week!
再也别想在这打篮球了
And you'll never play basketball here again.
别指望了
That you can count on.
你别想开除我 史威夫帝
You can't kick me off the team, Swifty.
为什么
Oh? Why is that?
因为我要退出篮球队...
'Cause I quit the team...
退学 再也不要见到你这个同性恋了
and the school and this whole faggot-ass scene, that's why.
我也一样
I could second that motion.
接受你们的请求
Your resignations are accepted!
纽琼 跟我们走吗
Neutron, you coming with us?
我猜到了
Yeah. That's what I figured.
我他妈的想快点离开这里
Come on, man. I'm fucking out of here.
别担心 史威夫帝 我不会把你供出来
Don't worry, Swifty. I'm not going to rat you out.
下辈子 神父
And in the next life, Father,
我要掌握大权
I'm going to have the paddle!
滚出去
Get out!
谢谢你 纽琼
Thanks a lot, Neutron.
谢谢
Thanks, man.
我真不敢相信
I can't believe this, you know?
我知道 那些药呢
I know. What happened to the pills?
我们被学校开除了 米奇
We got kicked out of the school, Mickey.
谁在乎啊 我们把药丢了 警察给拿走了
Who cares, man? We lost the pills. The cops took them
我们不能再打球了
We can't play ball anymore.
吉姆 谁在乎学校啊
Jim, who cares about school, man?
我们刚把四十块钱的药丢了
We just lost $40 worth of pharmaceuticals.
我知道它们会到哪去
I know what happened to them, too.
那些臭警察 他们也嗑
The cops, they take that all the time.
不是他们自己嗑了
They either pop them themselves
就是卖给别人
or they sell them.
等我回了家 我妈会怎么说啊
What's my mom going to say, man? When I go home?
她什么都不会说的
She ain't gonna say nothing.
就跟她说你每天早上去上学
You just tell her you're going to school every day in the morning.
我们走吧
Let's get out of here, man...
去找点东西
Go get into something.
你没在学校操场卖过药
You never sold any pills at the schoolyard?
没有
No.
所以是有人陷害你了 吉姆
So it's all a big conspiracy against you. Right, Jim?
嗯 可能是吧
Yeah. Maybe it is.
可能不是
Maybe it's not.
你忘了这个了
You been missing these?
你打算怎么说... 这是维生素
What are you going to tell me... they're vitamins?
滚蛋 妈
Oh, fuck you, Ma.
你说什么
What?!
滚出我家
Get out of my house!
你想这样是吗 妈
Oh, is that what you want, Ma?
出去 你不能这样和我说话
Get out! You don't talk to me that way!
如果你想这样 我马上就走 成了吧
If that's what you want, I'm fucking out of here. All right?
你在干吗
What are you doing?
我走了 你说我在干吗
I'm leaving! What do you think?
把你这些垃圾都拿走 我帮你 给
I want you to take all your shit! I'll help you. Here!
都拿走 该死
Take it! Crap!
你想让我走
You want me to leave?
是的 滚吧
Yes. Get out!
我马上走 别挡着我
I'm out of here. Get the fuck out of my way!
毒品会害死你的 吉姆
This garbage is going to kill you, Jim!
我走了
I'm gone!
会害死你的
Gonna to kill you!
你不明白吗 我不能看着你害死自己
Don't you understand? I can't watch you kill yourself?
妈 你再也不会看到我了
Ma, you're never going to fucking see me again, alright?
记住
Just remember that.
别这样说 吉姆 别这样说
Don't say that, Jim. Don't say that!
就像一场梦 不是噩梦...
It was a dream, not a nightmare...
而是在无数次打盹中做的
a beautiful dream I could never imagine
我永远想象不到的美梦
in a thousand nods.
我看见了身旁的这个姑娘
I saw this girl next to me
她笑起来很美
who wasn't beautiful until she smiled,
她的微笑向我袭来
and I felt that smile come at me
像有一股暖流
and heat waves following,
涌入我的身体 从我的指尖流出
soaking through my body and out my fingertips
射出一束光芒
in shafts of color.
我知道在这世界的某个地方...
And I knew somewhere in the world...
某个地方... 会有人来爱我
somewhere... that there was love for me.
我们只要有钱
We just got to raise enough cash
就能抬起头做人
to keep our heads straight.
幸运的是 在纽约抢钱
Luckily, finding money in New York
就像在舞会上找个人上床一样简单
is like getting laid at the prom... easy.
妈的 佩得 你干什么呢
Fuck it, Pedro! What's the matter with you?
看着路 你要杀了我们啊
Jesus! Watch the road. You could kill us all, c'mon!
这车值一千五
I get 1,500 bucks for this car.
要是撞坏了 就一个子不值了
If it's whacked up, it's worth nothing.
我们能买一大堆货了
We should buy shit in bulk, man
我们可以拿到街上做大买卖
We'll put it on the street and make real money.
一片五百块
That's 500 bucks a piece.
够我们花很多天 几周时间都可以
We'll be on for days, nights, weeks.
是啊 我很想去波多黎各
Yeah, man. I'd love to go to Puerto Rico,
晒晒日光浴
soak up some rays, you know?
见我的妞儿去
See my bitch?
我是这么想的
That's what I'd like to do.
你说什么 什么妞儿
What are you talking about? What bitch?
我们连张照片都没见过
We haven't seen a picture or nothing.
她有五百磅 吉姆
She's 500 pounds, Jim.
她的胡子比她爸还多
She got a mustache thicker than her father.
不 那是你妈 米奇
No. That's your mother, Mickey.
你根本没女人 别做梦了
She does not exist. Don't fool yourself.
帮我个忙 小心点 我要注射了
Do me a favor. Be careful. I'm about to whack.
该死
Oh, shit, man.
我哥会来照顾我们和这辆车的
My brother's going to take care of us and this car.
佩得 醒醒
Pedro, wake the fuck up!
佩得 嘿
Pedro, come on, man!
你要杀了我们啊 你在干吗
You're going to get us killed, what are you doing?
没事的 没事的
I got it, man. I got it.
让我开车吧
You want me to drive?
米奇 最好你来开车 说真的
Mickey, you better drive the car. I'm serious, man.
别扫了我的兴
Just don't blow my high.
如果这车刮坏了 我哥会杀了我
If there's a scratch in the car, my brother'll kill me.
从电话亭里出来
Yo, get out of the booth!
快点出来
Get out the booth, huh?
出来
Get out.
妈的...
Fucking...
怎么了
What's up? What's up?
我忙着呢 车在哪
Come on, I'm in a hurry. Where's the car?
见到你很高兴 就在那儿
It's good to see you, too. It's over here.
不错 非常棒的车
It's nice. It's smokin'.
说真的
You tell me that?
绝对是你要的那种
It's everything you wanted.
把你的手拿开 你们可真脏
Get your hands off. You guys look like shit.
哦 天啊
Oh, my God.
他们要把车拖走了
They're taking the car.
哪里有标识啊
Show me the sign, man!
哪他妈的有标识
Show me the freaking sign!
就在那 看见了吗
It's right there. You see?
写着 "停车拖走"
It says "tow-away." Huh?
你们这些废物不识字吗
You scumbags even read?
我要抽死你们
I should kick all your punk asses!
该死的
Goddamn it!
我今晚再给你弄一辆来
I can get you another car tonight.
约翰·海里根等着用这车呢
Yeah? John Halligan is waiting for this car.
我把他从床上叫起来了
I got him out of bed with his wife.
你知道这样会让我多难堪吗
You know how this makes me fucking look?
肯尼 放开
Kenny, get off.
我怎么有你这样的白痴弟弟
You're too stupid to be my brother!
你真蠢 放开他
You're too stupid! Get you off.
你也想试试吗 卡罗
You want a piece of me, Carroll?
滚开
Back off! Back off!
肯尼 别打了 狠角色
Kenny, no more! Mr. Tough Guy.
Kenny, no more! Huh? Tough guy?
给我喝一口汽水
Give me a sip of your soda.
你喝之前还擦擦
You wipe off the bottle before you take a sip?
你和米奇一起吸毒的时候想都没想
You don't even think twice about sharing works with Mickey.
你以为你会从瓶子上得上什么病么
You think you'll catch something from the bottle
针头就没事
you're not catch from a needle?
你以为我会在乎么
You mistake me for somebody who gives a shit.
指挥部... 离家回家
Headquarters... home on and off
从14街到鲍威街
to every down-and-out junkie and wino
每个被击垮的瘾君子和酒鬼
from 14th Street to the Bowery.
就像个全明星队
It's like a fucking all-star team.
吉米 那天
Jimmy, the other day,
我妈一直在我耳边说
my mother's been ragging on me,
"耶稣 玛利亚 约瑟夫啊
"Jesus, Mary, and Joseph.
"你尝试了所有的办法 去教堂吧
"You've tried every other way. Go to church.
把自己交给上帝"
Put yourself in Christ's hands."
我那样做了 我想去试试吧
So I do it, man. I figure, give it a shot.
我去找耶稣
I dig Jesus.
我去了 集会 唱诗班等等
So, I go, man. High mass... a choir and everything.
我首先在边上的祭坛上看到的是
The first thing I see on the right, the side altar,
红色杯子里的小小蜡烛
are those little candles in the red glass
就是我们在大风天里在公园里
that we used when it was windy in the park
做饭用的那种
to cook up.
然后 祭坛上的男孩 手里拿着6英尺的蜡烛
And then, this altar boy, he's coming down the aisle
走了下来
with this 6-foot candle.
我想象着往上面放个大勺子
I envision this huge spoon above it, man,
里面放着满满购物袋的毒品
with, like, shopping bags full of dope inside of it.
绝妙的事情发生了
And then the kicker comes, man.
神父 他开始用烟熏
The priest, he starts doing the thing with the incense.
味道飘了出来
You know, starts wafting out.
我在后面 最后终于闻到了
I'm in the back. It finally hits me.
"我在哪里闻过这个味道
"Where do I know this smell from, man?
我的房间里"
My room, man."
闻起来就像
It's the smell exactly
纯正的毒品被煮沸的味道
of really primo dope cooking up.
真的
Yeah?
一模一样
Exactly the same.
之后怎么着了
So what happened next?
这时候 我溜了出来
At that point, I split.
我回家了
I went home,
进了我的衣柜
I went inside my closet,
我把藏起来的毒品从复活节的
I got my stash out of the inside pocket
鲨皮衣服内兜里拿来出来
of my sharkskin easter suit,
我惊呆了
and I got stoned.
巴乒
Ba bing...
巴乓
ba bang.
我爱宗教仪式
I love a ritual.
圣母玛利亚 如果您能听见我...
Oh, Mary, if you can hear me...
请给予吉姆一点爱
I need you to fill Jim's heart with love
因为他真的很需要
because he really needs it now.
上帝啊...
Oh, God...
请照顾我的儿子
please watch over my son.
现在他需要您
He needs you now.
请照顾好他 可以吗
Just take care of him, okay?
我会没事的
I'll be okay.
我爱你 吉姆
I love you, Jim.
我爱你
I love you.
你有吗 直接点
Hey, you holding? You straight, man?
走开
Get out of here.
快点
Come on.
没有
No.
你看见法尔克了吗
Hey, have you seen Falco?
你有没有货
Come on, man. Are you holding anything?
嘿 戴安... 过来 戴安
Hey, Diane... Come here, Diane.
我会照顾你的 宝贝 是吗
I'll take care of you, babe. Yeah?
来点这个怎么样 哈哈
Yeah. How about some of this? Ha ha!
给我一包我也不干 你这垃圾
I wouldn't do you for a bag, you fucking piece of shit.
吉姆
Jim.
吉米
Jimmy.
你看起来不错
You're looking good.
谁来给你收尸啊
Who's your embalmer?
分我一点吧
I want some of what you got.
看看这里都有什么
Check everything in this place.
我一直想用这些糖浆机
Wow. I always wanted to use these syrup pumps.
还有这些专业的冰激凌勺
And these professional ice-cream scoopers.
哦 天
Oh, my God.
别逼我
Don't make me do it!
我发誓我会开枪的
I'll do it! I swear to God!
吉姆 小心
Jim, watch out.
快点
Come on!
打不开
It's not opening.
他们把设计改了
They don't make them like this anymore.
你得从边上打开它
You got to get it from the side.
我打开了
I got it!
酷
Oh, cool.
全是零钱
Change!
妈的
Shit!
我们走吧
Let's get out of here.
锁着的 我们得从后面走
It's locked. We got to go out the back.
佩得 快走
Pedro, let's get out of here!
这是我的幻觉吗
What am I, hallucinating here?
佩得 你会害我们被抓的
Pedro, you'll get us caught.
警察快来了
The cops are going to come.
你想来硬的是吗
Oh, you want to be tough, huh?
继续啊... 再喝一口
Go ahead... take another sip
我就把你的头打爆
so I can blow your fucking head all over the counter!
喝啊 佩得 喝
Go ahead, Pedro! Go ahead!
快点 快走
Come on, guys! Let's go.
把枪拿开
Put that gun away!
别和我对着干 傻逼
Don't fuck with me, motherfucker!
你丫在干吗 米奇
What the hell are you doing, Mickey?
你干吗这样
What the hell did you do that for?
让他自己待着吧
Let that little spic rot, man!
他会害我们被抓的
He'll get us caught.
吉姆 警察来了 快走
Jim, the cops are coming. Come on!
吉姆
Jim!
佩得 佩得
Pedro! Pedro!
吉姆
Jim!
别动 别动
Freeze! Freeze!
趴下 趴下
On your stomach! On your stomach!
我什么也没干
I didn't do anything, I'm telling you!
就这些
This is it, man.
那个犹太人肯定把钱藏枕头底下了
That Jew got to keep the money under his pillow.
吉姆 我知道你在为佩得的事生气
Hey, Jim, I know you're still mad about Pedro.
我也无能为力啊
I couldn't do nothing, man.
他差点害我们被抓
He was going to get us caught.
事情不该发展成这样的
Definitely shouldn't have went that far.
你怎么了 被你妈揍了
What happened to you? Your mother kick your ass?
真好笑
Yeah, real funny.
来两杯可乐
Bring us a couple of Cokes, will you?
你没事吧
You all right?
嘿 酒保 让开点
Hey, bartender, move out of the way.
吉姆 我有点恶心 我得去弄点钱
Jim, I'm getting sick. I got to get some money to cop.
吉姆
Jim.
听见我说话了吗
You with me here?
你在干吗
What the hell are you wa...
该死
Oh, shit.
纽琼
That's Neutron.
全美高中联赛
That's the all-American high school game?
我们本来也能参加这比赛的
We could have played in that game.
谁在乎啊 走吧
Who gives a shit? Come on.
我在等圣约翰学校的奖学金的消息...
I'm waiting to hear back on a scholarship from Saint John's...
还不是很确定 但希望能成功
I'm not sure about it, but hopefully it will work out.
吉姆 我毒瘾发作了
Jim, I'm starting to jones.
走吧 我们得去找点钱
Gotta get out there. We need some money.
吉姆 别做梦了
Jim, don't dwell on these dreams, man.
你走不走
Will you come on?
在外面等你 我受不了了
Meet you outside, man. I'm getting sick.
你出不出来啊
You want to meet me out there?
能让我和妈妈打个招呼吗
Is it okay if I say hi to my mom?
嗨 妈妈
Hi, Mom.
谢谢 很感谢你
Thanks. Thanks a lot.
# 你一无所知 但你还是来了 #
# You don't know it, but you're coming right along #
# 请坚强一点 #
# Please be strong #
# 你一无所知 但你还是来了 #
# You don't know it, but you're coming right along #
你 停下 你不能进去 停下
Hey, you! Stop! You can't go in there! Stop!
你要干吗
What do you want?
你知道几点了吗
You realize what time it is?
温基和布兰基在吗
Yeah. Um... is Winkie and Blinkie here?
温基和布兰基是谁
Who the hell are Winkie and Blinkie?
嘿
Hey, guys.
丽萨 梅 你们认识他
Lisa, Mel, you know this boy?
不认识 爸爸
No, Daddy.
不要啊
Come on.
行了
All right.
快滚出去
Come on. Get out of here.
抱歉 鲁宾先生 他溜进来了
I'm sorry, Mr. Rubin. He got past me.
不要再有第二次了
Don't let it happen again.
没下次了 快滚出去
It won't happen again. Get out of here!
干吗 干吗
What? What?
混蛋
Asshole.
你他妈起来
Hey, fuck-up, get fucking up, man!
你有什么毛病 你有什么毛病
What's your problem, man? What's your problem, mam?
你把垃圾卖给我女朋友了
You sold my girlfriend some shit the other day.
差点杀了她 你卖的是什么... 老鼠药
You almost killed her. What was it... rat poison?
与我无关 是你女朋友不会磕
It's not my fault your girl can't handle her drugs.
把二十块钱还给我
I want my fucking $20 back, man.
没有退钱这一说
Look, there's no money-back guarantees.
我这不卖雪柜
I'm not selling refrigerators here.
是吗 那这样呢
Oh, yeah? Check this out!
我给你在墨西哥那批货上打个折扣
I'll cut you a dynamite deal on mexican shit.
把二十块钱给我 要不然就到外面解决
Give me my $20, or we'll go outside.
到了外面 我们其中一个就会受伤的
If we go outside, one of us is going to get hurt.
我说了有个人会受伤的
I told you one of us would get hurt.
不是吗
Is that right?
写作最近变得有些困难...
It's been hard... the writing... lately.
没有灵感 随后又突然闪现...
Terrible numbness, then suddenly it comes...
在美丽的碎片或是可怕的噩梦里
in beautiful fragments or terrible dreams...
来回摆动
like nods...
非常兴奋
so high.
雷吉 是你吗
Reggie, is that you?
不然你以为是谁
Who the fuck do you think it is?
别担心
Don't worry,
你还没死
you're not dead yet.
还不错
It's not bad.
还给我
Hey, give me that.
怎么都湿了
How come it's all wet?
因为你尿的
Because you pissed on it.
我没说你可以看我的文章
I didn't say you could read this.
你把我的文章都看了
What, have you been digging through all my stuff?
我得... 我得走了
I need... I got to get out of here.
我的衣服呢
Where's my jacket?
不客气
You're welcome.
我为什么要谢你
What the hell am I thanking you for?
因为你差点在雪地里冻死
Because you was frozen in the snow like a goddamn creamsicle.
在哪
Where is it?
什么
What?
你知道我说的是什么
You know what the fuck I'm talking about,
雷吉 你放哪了
Reggie! Where is it?
你说这个
You mean this?
给我
Give it to me.
我要杀了你
I'll cut your fucking throat,
雷吉 还给我
Reggie! Give it to me, all right?
快给我
Just give it to me!
还给我
Oh, give it to me!
还给我 我说真的
Give it to me! I'm serious!
给我
Give me it!
Give it to me!
你妈的
Goddamn it!
我对你实在太好了
I'll make you an incredible offer.
我一天要救你两次 明白吗
I'm going to save your life twice in one day, understand me?
你应该把我留在雪地里
You should have left me in the fucking snow, man.
给我买毒品的钱
Give me the money for my dope, too.
我才不会帮你吹箫 离我远点
I'm not gonna suck your dick, all right? Put that away.
谁要你帮我吹箫啊
Who the hell wants you to suck their dick?
该死
Goddamn it!
看看你自己 看看
Look at yourself! Just look at yourself.
雷吉
Oh, Reggie...
没事的
it's okay.
你为什么要这样做
Why are you doing this?
因为从前 也有个人帮过我
Because once upon a time, somebody helped me,
我总想把这份善心传递给别人
and I always pay what I owe.
雷吉
Reggie.
雷吉 我就抽一口
Reggie, I just need a taste.
就一点 雷吉
I just need a little something, Reggie.
你不明白
You don't understand.
难受死了 雷吉
It hurts, Reggie!
雷吉 我要走
Reggie, I got to go.
我要找我妈
I got to go see my mom.
你得让我出去 雷吉
You got to let me get out of here, Reggie.
雷吉
Reggie!
好疼... 好疼
It hur... It hurts.
啊 该死
Aah! Shit!
哦 孩子...
Oh, boy...
# 触摸吧 尝尝吧 #
# Touch the taste and taste the smell #
# 尝尝味道 你给予我的所有天赋 宝贝 #
# Smell the scent, all the gifts you gave to me, baby #
# 你的精神粮食 #
# The food of your brain #
# 屋子在旋转 #
# The room is spinning round #
# 我从未倒下过 #
# I never come down #
# 屋子在旋转 #
# The room is spinning round #
# 我从未倒下过...
# I never come down... #
雷吉
Reggie.
给我点吧
you got to give me it.
给我 雷吉
You got to give me it, Reggie.
求你了
Please! Oh!
雷吉 快点
Reggie, come on!
# 我也记得你 #
# I remember you, too #
# 我失去了控制 #
# I blew my mind #
醒醒 别整天睡觉
Wake up. Can't sleep all day.
谢谢
Oh. Thanks.
天
Jesus Christ.
你怎么了
What happened to you?
你说呢 有人开枪射我
What does it look like? Motherfucker shot me.
把我的屁股打开花儿了
Woke my black ass up.
该死
Shit.
我早上回来 吉姆
Look, uh... l'll be back in the morning, Jim.
你待在这
You just stay cool.
要是毒瘾上来了
You start to get panicky,
就在你的本上写写我
write about me in that book of yours.
事实上你从没在上面提及过我让我有点伤心
Actually, I was a little hurt I wasn't mentioned.
你真的很喜欢我写的东西 是吧 雷吉
You really like my writing, huh, Reggie?
跟你说了四次了
Damn, man, I told you four times already.
你想让我怎么做 弯下腰亲你的屁股吗
What do you want me to do? Bend over and kiss your ass?
雷 帮我个忙
Hey, Reg, do me a favor.
在外面给我找一包回来
While you're out, pick me up a bag.
# 屋子在旋转 #
# The room is spinning round #
# 也许我永远不会停下 #
# I may never come down #
我是独自一人
I am alone.
不只是我
Not just me.
我们都是独自一人...
We're alone...
永远是一个人
alone forever.
谁等在我飞奔而过的永恒隧道的尽头
And who's at the end of that forever tunnel I run through,
上面是高楼鳞次栉比的第五大道
up Fifth with the wallpaper of skyscrapers?
我在想 在这些美好的旅途之后
I'm thinking, after all those beautiful trips,
这是其中糟糕的一回
that this is one of those bad ones.
戴安
Diane?
嘿
Hey!
我是吉姆 还记得我吗
Jim. Remember me?
你精神不错
Man, you look great.
嗯 谢谢
Yeah, thanks.
能遇见到老邻居真是不错
Good to see somebody from the old neighborhood...
你想干吗 吉姆
What do you want, Jim?
你有钱么 没有
You holding anything? No.
只要5块钱就行了
Just like a 5 or something?
帮我一下吧
Just to tide me over, you know?
求你了 戴安
Please, Diane? Come on.
我们是老朋友吗 当然了
Yeah. For an old friend? Why not?
我已经走了好长一段路了
I've been looking all over for this.
我只有二十块面值的钞票
Oh, you know what? I only got a 20.
二十也不错
A 20 is good.
真的 真的
Yeah? Yeah!
有二十块太好了 能帮我大忙了
A 20 is great, yeah. That would help me out a lot.
你想要 对
You want a 20? Yeah.
给你自己去买点饼干吃吧 混蛋
Why don't you go buy yourself some pretzels, you asshole.
婊子 你就是只鸡
You bitch! You're nothing but a whore!
我不管你穿着什么衣服
I don't give a shit about your clothes!
对我来说你就是只鸡
You're still a whore to me!
闭嘴吧 看看你自己 多么绝望啊
Yeah? Shut up. Look at you. Oh, are you desperate now, baby?
现在谁是鸡
Who's a whore now?
别那样和我说话 婊子
Don't talk to me like that, you bitch!
哈哈 谁笑到了最后 白痴
Ha ha. Who's laughing, stupid?
别想耍我 我知道你
Don't play a game with me! I know you!
妈的
Shit. Oh, man.
Shit.
米奇
Mickey.
米奇 你好吗
Mick, what's up, man?
你好吗
Hey, what's up, man?
你还有钱么
Did you get anything?
一分钱都没了 你呢
No, not a dime. You score?
我还有点钱
Yeah, I got something.
有多少
What'd you get?
大概三十五块钱
About 35 bucks.
三十五块 你从哪搞到的
35? Where'd you get it?
我在四号线地铁上抢的
I robbed some fucking asshole on the "D" train.
三十五块钱够我们用两天呢
Dude, 35 will keep us on for, like, two days.
咱们能买到吗
Well, could we get some stuff, man?
我他妈... 脑袋...
I'm fucking... my head is...
我看到几个西班牙人 应该能成
I see some spics. I think we can score.
去看看吗
You wanna check it out?
好 走 他们在那儿
Yeah, alright. Come on. They're over here.
为什么大街上总是有警察
Why the fuck do we have to cop on the street all the time?
我下面痒死了
My fucking nuts are itching like crazy.
是他吗
Think this is him?
你是叫皮诺吗
Is your name Pino?
能给我们弄点货么
Listen... could we get us some dope?
那边那个人说你能帮忙
The dude over there said you could help.
你们想买
You want to cop some shit?
把钱先给我看看
Let me see some cash.
我有钱
I got it here.
给我看看
Let me see.
不给尝一下就没钱
Hey, no money without no taste.
你想尝
You want a taste?
别担心 别担心
Don't worry. Don't worry.
快点
Hurry, man.
快点 这都是警察
Come on. There's fucking cops all over.
很不错 不错
That's good, man. That's good.
听着 四个三十五块
All right, listen... 4 for 35.
四个三十五块
4 for 35, man?
拜托 就少了五块了
Come on, man. $5.00 short.
有什么大不了的 好吧 给你
What's the big deal? Ta bien, chico...Toma, toma.
拿到了吗 嗯
You got four? Yeah.
我们得尝尝
We should taste this.
我们刚尝过了 我们去哪煮
We just tasted this. Where are we going to cook it up?
那个家伙我不太熟悉
I don't know about his guy.
没事 他还不错
No, he's cool.
操
Fuck, man!
怎么了
What's the matter?
你再尝尝 什么意思 我尝过了
Just taste it! Come on. What do you mean? I tasted it.
他耍了我们 他妈的耍了我们
He beat us. He fucking beat us.
我向他妈的上帝发誓...
I swear to fucking God...
把枪拿开
Put that away!
我要杀了这个混蛋
I'm gonna kill this mothe...!
站住 傻逼 把枪拿开
Come here, motherfucker! Put it away!
我发誓我他妈的要杀了你
I swear to god. I'm going to fucking kill you,
傻逼
you motherfucker!
傻逼 你丫死定了 听见了吗
Motherfucker, you're fucking dead, you hear me?
你给我站住
Make a stand, you hear me?
别逼我
Dude, don't make me do it.
我的钱呢
Where's the money?
把钱还给我 钱还有药
I want the money. I want the money and the bags.
钱在哪
Where's the fucking money?
钱 还给我
The fucking money! I want it!
不
No!
哦 糟了 我们杀了他
Oh, shit! We fucking killed him!
你说我们是什么意思
What the fuck do you mean, we?
我根本没碰他
I didn't fucking touch him!
你别把责任推给我
Don't put that shit on me!
他耍了我们 他活该
He beat us, man! He deserved it!
你玩得太过了 米奇 该死
You went too far, Mickey! Oh, shit!
他死了么
Is he dead?
当然他妈的死了 他从六层掉下去的
Of course he's fucking dead! He fell six stories!
吉姆 走吧
Jim, come on.
走啊 你走不走
Come on! Will you come one?
吉姆 别逼我留你一个人在这
Jim, don't make me leave you here!
妈的
Oh, shit.
# 星星 #
# Star #
# 我伸手就能够到你 #
# I'll reach you if I try #
# 告诉我真相 #
# Show me the truth, yeah #
# 星星 #
# Star #
# 我伸手就能够到你 #
# I'll reach you if I try #
# 告诉我真相 #
# Show me the truth, yeah #
起来啊
Come on, get back up! Come on!
放开我 你们干吗
Get off of me! What are you doing?
谁啊
Who is it?
妈... 让我进去
Ma... let me in.
妈 让我进去
Ma, let me in!
求你了 妈
Please, Ma.
妈 妈
Ma? Hey, Ma?
你在吗 妈
Are you in there, Ma?
妈 是你吗
Ma, is that you?
是
Yeah.
妈 妈
Ma? Ma?
你在吗 嗯
Are you there? Yeah.
嗨
Hi.
嗨 妈
Hi, Ma.
嗨 嗨
Hi. Hi.
你得帮帮我 好吗
Listen, I need you to help me out, all right?
你得给我点钱
I need you to give me some money.
好吗
Okay?
你得给我 五块
I need you to give me, like, five doll...
或者二十块钱
Like, $20, something like that
我惹了点麻烦
because I'm in some trouble.
妈
Ma?
你听见了吗 妈
Do you hear me, Ma?
我听见了 我帮不了你
Yeah, I hear you. I can't help you.
听着
Okay, listen,
你只需要给我点钱
what you got to do is give me some money, okay?
吉姆 我不能给你
Jim, I can't do that.
为什么
Why not?
妈 我不会乱花的
Mom, you know I'm not going to do anything with it.
我得出城一段时间
I just need to go out of town for a little while
我惹麻烦了
'cause I got into some trouble,
我需要帮助
and I need some help.
你得给我点钱 妈
Okay? So, you got to give me some money, Mom.
你能握住我的手吗
Can you hold my hand?
我会的
Yeah, I'll hold your hand.
妈 给我点钱吧 求你了
Mom, can you give me some money, please?
别闹了
Stop fucking around!
我不能给你
I can't.
妈 给我点钱
Mom, give me some fucking money, please!
你怎么能这样 我是你儿子
What are you doing? I'm your son!
我没钱
I don't have any.
妈 别这样对我
Mom, don't fuck around like this!
给我点钱
Give me some money!
妈
Mom!
让我进去
Come on! Let me in the fucking door!
上帝啊
Oh, God.
操
Oh, fuck.
让我进去
Let me in.
我需要钱
I need some money.
我真的很需要钱
I need some money real bad.
哦
Ohh...
上帝
Oh, God.
有人要闯进我家
Someone's breaking into my apartment.
他们有刀
They have a knife.
哦
Oh!
妈
Mom!
你不明白 妈
You don't understand, Mom.
你不知道你在做什么
You don't know what you're fucking doing to me.
我很痛苦
Mom, I'm in pain.
你怎么能这样对你的儿子 你这个婊子
How could you do this to your son, you bitch?
臭婊子
You fucking bitch!
让我进去
Oh, let me in!
让我做什么都行 我会乖的
I'll do anything! I'll be a good boy!
我会乖的 妈
I'll be a good boy, mom,
让我进去
if you let me in.
放开我
Get off me!
放开
Get off!
不
No!
你们这些混蛋
You fuckers!
你们不能抓我 操
You're not going to do this! Fuck you!
妈 别这样
Ma! Don't do this!
妈
Ma!
我因为袭击 抢劫
I got six months in Riker's Island
拒捕和藏毒
for assault, robbery,
在雷克岛监狱待了六个月
resisting arrest, and possession of narcotics.
我经历了痛苦的戒毒过程
I sweated out a horrible cure
再也没有碰过毒品
and stayed clean the whole stretch
即便在狱中比在街上
even though it's been easier to get good junk in here
更容易搞到好货
than it is on the street.
真的很痛苦
Shit, it's been hard, man.
我一直在读我的日记
All I've been doing is reading these diaries
思考着我是怎么活到今天的
and wondering how the hell I'm still alive,
我究竟在乎什么
and even if I care.
可以说那些恶棍 不会再在浴室里欺负我了
with the asshole bandits of shower-room rape,
可以说那些猪猡看守
and suffice to say that those swine guards
不会再把我的脚腕子打出血了
won't draw blood from my ankles again.
可以说我一直在想这一件愚蠢的事
Suffice to say that I've been just thinking about dumb stuff
就是如果我要是有教母和教父
like what a nice concept
该有多好
it is to have a godmother and a godfather,
思索着我的教父母会是谁
wondering who my godparents might be.
我妈不会来这看我
My mom won't visit me here,
所以我只能等回家之后再问她了
so I guess I'll just have to wait till I get home to ask.
吉姆
Jim?
谁啊
Who's there?
我
It's me.
佩德
Pedro?
你怎么样
What's up, man?
还行
Nothing. You know.
我听说你回来了
l... I hear you come here.
过来和你打个招呼
I just came by to say hi.
那天晚上在糖果店
I'm sorry about that night
是我对不起你
at the candy store and everything.
没事 少管所其实还不错
It's all right. Reform school turned out to be real cool,
别放在心上了
so don't sweat it.
你听说米奇那个混蛋的事了么
Did you hear about Mickey, that scumbag?
他把一个人从楼顶推下来了
He went and threw some chump off a roof.
他要被判五至十五年了
He's getting 5 to 15 years, man.
他们要把他按成人判罪
They tried him like an adult.
妈的
Shit.
我给你带了点东西 吉姆
I got a present for you, Jim.
全曼哈顿
A bag of the finest dope
最好的毒品
in Manhattan.
怎么样 我和你
You know, me and you?
和原来一样
Like old times?
我不能
I can't.
会很爽的
Come on. It would be dynamite.
我还有事做
I got this thing to do.
你等会来不行吗
Why don't you come check it out?
不行 我现在就去 明白吗
No. I'm going to go, then, you know?
你明白我的意思
You know how it is.
照顾好自己 小家伙
Take care of yourself, little man.
下回见 吉姆
See you around, Jim.
你得知道
Know this.
吸毒的人有不同的类型
There's different types of users of junk.
那些有钱的业余爱好者
You got your rich dilettante square-ass
没事抽一抽
who dabbles now and then
如果觉得玩得过火了
and always has enough money to run off to the Riviera
还总是有足够的钱跑到里维埃拉(度假胜地)
if he feels he's fucking around to the danger point.
街头的毒贩最恨他们
Street junkies hate these pricks,
但这些人是常客
but they're always suckers,
给的钱也令人满意
and their money makes them tolerable.
然后就是中上阶级的人
Then you got your upper-middle-class
维斯切斯特的大学预备生们...
Westchester preppies...
基本和其他人差不多
same as the others, basically.
他们有用之处就是让他们的爸妈睁开眼睛
What they're good for is opening their mommy and daddy's eyes
看到这些社会渣滓
to this social virus
然后再对政府施压
and putting pressure on the government
让政府来解决这个问题
to do something about it.
然后就是我们这些街头孩子了
Then there's us street kids.
很小的时候就出来鬼混
Start fucking around very young,
也就十三岁上下...
13 or so...
我们以为自己能控制好一切
We think we all got it under control
不会吸毒成瘾
and won't get strung out.
但事情很少如我们所愿
This rarely works.
我就是个活生生的例子
I'm living proof.
但最终你只是会把它
But in the end, you just got to see the junk
看作是一场日场演出
as another 9-to-5 gig.
一场被黑暗笼罩着的演出
The hours are just a bit more inclined to shadows.
吉姆·卡罗在17岁时完成了他的"篮球日记"
在22岁时出版了3部著名诗集 并录制了4张专辑
如今 吉姆·卡罗住在纽约城 继续写作
他现在是一名受人喜爱的诗人 音乐人 小说家和演员
谢谢观赏
-=圣城家园 CnSCG 荣誉出品=-
hd.cnscg.com